## Matthew Richardson Full Stack Developer

#### **SUMMARY:**

Candidate is a web developer with 8 years professional experience in web development and a degree in Information Systems. He is currently at Nottingham as a full stack web developer. He led the development of the client portal and accounting reports using Vue JS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS:**

- 8 years of JavaScript and PHP experience.
- Hands on development with Vue.js, React.js, Node.js, and Laravel.
- Experience working with a team and building web apps from inception to deployment.

## **LINKEDIN PROFILE:**

#### **SKILLS:**

<u>Front-end:</u> Vue.JS, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, responsive mobile design, UI/UX Design, jQuery, AJAX <u>Back-end:</u> PHP, JavaScript, .NET

<u>Data Storage & Transfer:</u> SQL, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server Studio, PhpMyAdmin, dBeaver.

<u>Tools/Practices:</u> Git, GitHub, VS Code, Linux, Node.js, NPM, CI/CD, Vite, Composer, Object Oriented Programming, MVC, UI design, UX design, Agile

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

**Full Stack Web Developer** 

**Rocky Mount, NC** 

Nottingham 2014 - Present

- Created a shareholder transaction system using JavaScript on the front end and a PHP MVC API on the backend.
- Developed data-driven apps using MySQL and T-SQL.
- Led development, testing, deployment and deployment of client portal features such as user authentication, password management, email notification system, two-factor authentication, and session management, via PHP libraries and best practices.
- Raised awareness of cyber-attacks by developing the first cyber security training web app with JavaScript, ¡Query animations, Bootstrap AJAX and PHP.
- Awarded "Core Values Critical Thinker" Award for automating processes traditionally done with paper, saving resources and time, while utilizing technologies such as Linux, Apache, Nginx, PHP, MySQL and JavaScript.
- Secured data by adding encryption in MySQL databases and using PHP OpenSSL.
- Introduced modern responsive web designs, allowing clients to effectively view pages on any device, using HTML, CSS, and media queries.
- Eliminated Legal documentation obstacles by creating a questionnaire system that allowed Legal to create, send, schedule, and review questionnaires via JavaScript, and OOP PHP.
- Solved Software development documentation insufficiencies by creating a project management app to record support requests and project life cycles, while using JavaScript and PHP for handling HTTP requests.
- Secured sensitive documents by using Full-stack development to create a secure online file manager using PHP directory features. This allowed new and existing employees to create an account and upload files instead of sending over email.
- Ensured the best user experience by using JavaScript and AJAX, and front-end frameworks such as React.js and Vue.js

# Matthew Richardson Full Stack Developer

Freelance Web Design United States
Self-employed 2018 - Present

 Created an online Photography Portfolio using React, JSX and Node.js. Styled components using React-Bootstrap library. Used git for version control. Deployed the app using Netlify. Implement SEO best practices.

- Designed a website for an auto-repair shop. Used GitHub Pages for hosting and Bootstrap, CSS media queries, and Flexbox for mobile web design, while using FormSpree for contact forms.
- Experience configuring Shopify online stores.

## **EDUCATION:**

North Carolina Wesleyan College

**Rocky Mount, NC** 

**B.S., Information Systems** 

2010 - 2014

- Senior project resulted in creation of a website for listing rental properties using HTML, CSS, SQL and PHP.
- Learned best practices of programming while learning Java, C++, JavaScript, PHP, and Visual Basic
- Drummer for the Jazz Band and Pep Band